Stop.
Somebody's coming.
Are you serious, missy?
You must be crazy to travel alone.
O-Oh, I'll be fine.
I'm stronger than I look.
Also, um, my greetings.
I am a harmless little...
A-A lamia!
Do you have to get that scared?
A New Friend
Magical potions,
unlike regular medicine, is produced
using magic-infused ingredients.
As such, they need extra caution to prepare.
In the worst case,
the tiniest mistake in measurement or
magic infused can be life-threatening.
Dolan, you're not very dexterous, are you?
My apologies, master.
D-Don't put yourself down, Dolan!
You have a keen eye for medicinal herbs,
you're very good with the kids...
And you're handsome.
Oh, my.
Thanks, Airi.
But it's true that I find it hard
to follow complicated recipes.
I'll work on my precision.
I-I just... said what I thought.
There appears to be no problem with Airi's.
Really? Yay!
Yes.
You're done for the day. Go play outside.
Huh?
Oh, I guess I'll go help Mom out, then.
As a dragon in my past life,
medicine wasn't really necessary,
which is why I'm not skilled
with minute adjustments.
Your offensive magic is top-class,
but you just don't seem to be getting
the hang of magical medicine.
My apologies.
Well, no need to rush.
There are no shortcuts in life.
You have the talent, so a few hurdles
here and there should help you grow.
"Some know-how and a small
detour," as you always say?
Right.
I suppose I'll teach you how to turn
your poisonous failures into antidote.
I feel bad for partaking,
but thank you for the meal.
Don't worry about it.
We invited you, after all.
O Goddess of Nature, Myrale.
We thank you for your generosity.
Myrale...
May you bless our daily bread and our lives.
I haven't seen her in ages.
I stayed too long.
Hello, Dolan.
Isn't today training day?
It is. That's why I'm in a rush.
No time to drink some fresh milk, then?
Miu, a demihuman cowperson,
shares her milk with the
people of the village.
As for how it tastes...
Phew! Delicious!
It is divine.
Yeah, I should hurry...
Here you are.
I'll have some.
Thank you.
Good luck!
One!
Two!
You're nearly done. Keep at it.
Sorry I'm late, Albert.
Don't worry about it.
You were studying with old Maguru, right?
All right, kids. Take a break.
Okay!
Dolan, check my spear work.
Mine, too!
After your break.
We'll be fine.
Hey, follow your instructions.
What? Don't say that.
Come on!
Why?!
But I worked really hard!
I just felt a monster's presence...
What's up?
Nah, it's nothing.
That presence I felt this afternoon...
It was definitely a monster.
A familiar one, at that.
But they shouldn't be here.
So it was you after all, Celina.
Huh? D-Dolan?!
What are you doing here, Celina?
Dolan... Oh—
D-Don't look!
Wow, beautiful.
Oh, pardon me. My lack of
vocabulary is truly vexing.
Close your eyes!
Why? You're very pretty.
And being seen won't reduce your beauty.
Maybe so, but it's still embarrassing!
How can you be so unaffected, anyway?
Have some shame, will you?
Craving beautiful things
is a natural instinct.
There is nothing shameful about that.
My apologies. That was tactless of me.
It's fine. Forget it already.
So, what are you doing here?
I thought you headed south
in search of a husband.
That was the plan, yes...
I see. Most would run away, I guess.
So you came looking for me?
I-I find making contact
with humans scary, too.
Still, I worked up my courage to greet them,
only for them to run away terrified.
I was hoping to see you again,
so I'm glad you're here.
You mean it?
I do. I'll do anything I can to help.
Hmm, this might be a good idea, actually.
What do you mean?
What do you say, Celina?
Do you want to live together?
Huh?
What?!
Me? Live in your village?
I have a plan that'll help you to.
B-But I'm a monster, you know?
I'll only end up scaring all the humans.
Oh, many beastkin and demihumans
already live in the village.
They're part of our community.
B-But a lamia?
Sure, they may be wary of you at first,
but with your gentle personality
and lamia powers,
they'll soon welcome you with open arms.
I can... be friends with humans?
I think your presence would make life
that much more enjoyable for me.
Hm? Why does it sound
like I'm courting her?
I-I think life with you
would be very fun, too!
It would be wonderful if
we could make it happen.
Besides...
Besides?
There's another reason
I was looking for you.
I was kind of hoping you would share
some of your life energy with me again.
Oh, I'm glad you liked it.
I've never had such a delicious and
nourishing life energy before.
Once we start living together,
you can have it anytime.
Just like this...
It's so delicious...
Listen up. Here's my plan.
Captain, it happened again.
Hmm... That's three days in a row now.
This pit on the ground...
Doesn't it look like it was
made by a large snake?
That half-human, half-creature shadow
we saw last night was no illusion.
A lamia, a powerful and dangerous monster.
But why did it leave its prey here?
For what purpose?
Are you certain?
Yes.
They're said to be rare.
Why would one show up here?
But would an evil monster leave
an offering for us every day?
That sharke was delicious.
Yes, it was marvelous.
Ahem!
Excuse me.
Anyway, we must put together a
squad to eliminate it at once.
We must strike before anything bad happens!
Calm down, Balan.
A lamia is extremely
dangerous even by itself.
And this village only has you
and a few stationed soldiers.
I suggest we call for reinforcements
from the capital.
We should send a messenger
out at once, then.
I didn't know there was such a deep
divide between humans and monsters.
But they should understand once they
get to know Celina herself...
Stop panicking!
Balan, it is clear to everyone just
how much you care for this village.
And we're ever grateful for it.
But think about it.
It's leaving offerings for us.
There must be a reason for that.
And just wait a moment. She'll be here soon.
Excuse me. It's Airi.
Come on in.
Grandmother, the results of
the fortune-telling are in.
There we go.
Now show me the results, Airi.
Here.
It's the same result I got.
What does it say, Maguru?
"The appearance of a snake
is a sign of good fortune."
We should wait and see what it does.
Great. Now we can proceed to
the final phase of the plan.
The final phase of the plan, you say?
Yes.
The villagers seem a lot less wary now.
And the biggest threat, an elimination
squad, is looking unlikely.
The offerings strategy worked out.
You did well, Celina.
Oh, no, I only did as you said.
You even helped me hunt, too.
Anything to help you out.
Anyway, we just need to put
the finishing touches now.
Listen up. Here's what we're doing.
As you may have heard,
we've sighted a lamia.
It must still be nearby.
As remote settlers, it falls upon us to
learn how to defend our own villages!
Therefore, we will be holding our
outdoor training session as planned!
Balan's so cool.
Make sure you don't run off alone, kids!
Right? That's my dad for you.
Looks like most of the village's
big names are here.
Yes, they form the core of
the village's defenses.
They must really be on edge.
However, they're just the people
we need for our plan's finale.
The garrison is Verun Village's biggest force,
and its Captain Balan and
Vice Captain Malida are here.
Goddess Myrale,
Then there's the priestess Leticia,
follower of the Goddess of Nature Myrale.
please offer these villagers
She holds immense value for her ability
to use healing and antidote miracles.
your blessings and protection.
But she's also considered
the goddess's messenger.
If we're not careful, she may declare
Celina evil with no consideration.
It's up to you now, Celina.
If this works out,
you'll be welcomed into the village.
I'm so nervous...
I have to save you?
That's right.
Tomorrow's training venue happens
to be in piercing bunny territory.
I'll run into their den on purpose.
When I give the sign, come out and save me.
Once they see you do that, nobody will
take you to be a malicious monster.
When do I go? Not yet?
Now, Malida and I will each lead a squad.
What's wrong?!
Captain! I-It's here!
The lamia? All hands, alert!
Celina? I haven't given the sign yet!
Huh? There's another lamia?!
No, this presence is...
No! Not a lamia!
An armored bear!
Impossible.
What's an armored bear doing
at the edge of the forest?
Don't even think about attacking it!
It can kill you with one hit!
Keep your distance!
Tauro!
D-Dad...
He won't escape in one piece unless
I use my dragon powers, huh...
Watch out!
Ce...?!
Celina!
Wh-What's going on?
The lamia saved them?
You're okay now...
M-Miss...
Back to the forest with you.
The armored bear...
is going back into the forest.
Those must be the famed
cursed eyes. So powerful...
Are you all right?
Y-Yes.
And you, Dolan?
Not a scratch. But what about you?
Get away from Tauro and Dolan, lamia!
Run along, Tauro.
Huh? O-Okay...
You come too, Dolan.
She saved me. Don't hurt her.
Oh, don't worry about me...
Yes, she did seem to save him and Tauro.
But lamia are dangerous monsters.
I cannot let her be. I'm responsible
for the village's safety.
I wasn't taught to
return kindness with spite.
So I won't be moving from here.
Lamia!
Are you the one who has been leaving
offerings for the village?
Yes, that's right.
It wash me.
I misspoke.
Sh-She misspoke...
Wh-Why would you do that?
And why did you save Tauro and Dolan?
I am Celina the lamia.
I have a request!
Please let me live in your village!
I followed the rules of my kind
and left my home on a journey.
But traveling alone has been far more
lonely than I ever imagined.
I'm not asking to stay forever!
But please let me live with
you for a little while!
Also, I saved Do—these two
because their families would
be saddened by their deaths.
My dad was a human, and he and my
mom loved each other very much.
So I have no intention of
harming any humans, either.
Please, I beg of you!
Uh, she's not scary at all.
Kinda cute, if anything.
So Maguru's fortune-telling was right?
Leticia, what do you say?
Wh-What's happening?
Wait, could it be...
What's the matter?
Yes... Yes!
Leticia?
I have received an oracle
from Goddess Myrale.
Huh? From Goddess of Nature Myrale?
Yes, there's no mistaking it.
A divine judgment.
"The lamia before you is not evil.
She is a child of nature, just like you.
Live together in harmony," she says.
You're keeping your eyes closed to allay
our fear of your cursed eyes, aren't you?
You may open your eyes now, kind lamia.
Thank you so...
This is bad. Let's get her to the village!
R-Right! Let's hurry!
A home for me...?
Yes, but I'm sure lamia and humans
need very different things.
Check inside and see if it's acceptable.
Aren't you glad, Celina?
I am!
So soft.
The many cushions were Captain Balan's idea.
It seems you like it, huh?
Thank you so much for giving
me such a lovely home.
I'm sorry for pointing my weapon at you.
You saved my son's life.
Allow me to express my gratitude.
Thank you, really.
P-Please raise your head!
We don't know anything about lamia,
so I'm sure there's a lot were missing.
Please teach us all about yourself, Celina.
Oh no, I'm sorely lacking in
knowledge of humans myself.
Please teach me about yourselves, too.
Let's get to know each
other better as neighbors.
I'm Dolan. And you?
C-Celina.
Welcome to Verun Village, Celina.
Thank you!
Next Episode
This week's lucky item is sharke!
Look forward to next time!